# SHRADHA RAINA

# **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

Exp: 5.8 Years

## **CONTACT ME**

3155723149 | shradha59raina@gmail.com

# LINKEDIN | BEHANCE

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have nearly 6 years of experience in creative designing and adding value to the companies worked so far. I have worked in multiple companies in multiple cities from small setups to MNCs in India. I am known to different culture and workspace, so I can easily merge with the work environment. I have played lead roles in multiple tasks so know team management very well. Always open to new challenges and accomplish the company standards in the artwork. I take negative comments in positive way to enhance my skills and I am always ready to learn from anyone who has skills. I know vast in graphic designing, but I personally like doing minimalistic infographics. Doing abstract work is my forte. I enjoy my work. My passion is my profession. Currently pursuing for Art major in Graphic Designing from Onondaga Community College, Syracuse, New York.

#### **EDUCATION**

COLLEGE	DEGREE	YEAR
ONONDAGA COMMUNITY COLLEGE, EAST SYRACUSE, NEW YORK, US	AAS Degree in Arts Major (Graphic Designing)	2022-Pursuing
JAMIA MILLIA ISLAMIA UNIVERSITY, DELHI, INDIA	Bachelor Of Fine Arts (Art Education)	2006-2010
F-TECH (FORESIGHT TECHNICAL /EDUCATION), DELHI, INDIA	Certificate (DTP, Web Designing and Graphic Designing)	2010

SOFTWARE KNOWN	SKILLS
Adobe Illustrator	Logos, Flyers, Posters, Banners, Visiting Cards, Illustrations, 3D Drawings, Vector Images, Typography, Game Background, Masking, Infographics, Newsletters, Emailers, Flex, Icon design, Branding
Adobe Photoshop	Image editing, Web Page Layout (front end), Flyers, Posters, Flat Mockups, GIFs, Icons, Buttons, adding and removing background in an image

Adobe InDesign	Package Design, Book Page design, Newsletters, Emailers, Flex, Banners
Adobe Fireworks	Web Page Layout (front end)
Adobe Animate	2D animations, Interactive Pages (minor coding), Text animations, Infographics, realistic illustrations, sketch.
Adobe After Effects	Video editing, sound adding and subtracting, water mark adding and removing, background changes
Articulate 360	developing e-learning courses
MS PowerPoint	Impressive Presentations, animation slides, Infographics, look and feel of Presentations, Graphs, Icons, Banners, Flyers, Illustrations

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Infogain Pvt. Ltd. (User Interface Consultant)

## 1st Mar 2021- 29th Aug 2021, Noida

- Collaborate with clients, internal project teams, and managing director to understand project assignment, audience, and intended message.
- Provided onsite support and coordinating presentations.
- Provided thoughtful and appropriate critique and refine the work of others.
- Coordinated across teams to produce a slide template library that includes corporate color schemes and assets.
- Developed, produced, and lead well-thought-out presentations that tell the story of the design solution.
- Participate in calls/meetings with internal teams.
- Customized stakeholders PowerPoint templates within design standards.
- Created and maintained tools, templates, and slide deck libraries that assist colleagues in creating their own content.
- Designed visually appealing infographics.
- Provided basic proofreading during the design phase.
- Video editing with Adobe After effect: Removing or adding watermarks in the videos, Editing slides in videos.

### HCL (MTS, Sr. Graphic Designer)

## 17th May 2018- 9th Sep 2019, Chennai

- Creating schematics and Decks for labeling projects, Edit, verify, and proofread all the manuals and user guides created for medical equipment like AMS Ambicor, AMS 700, AMS 800, GreenLight XPS.
- Applying Brexit changes to the manuals and user guides.
- Modifying old PowerPoint with new infographics using latest version of graphic tools.
- Conceptualizing original ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex design roadblocks.
- Designing visually appealing infographics. Held a role as lead which included (Siemens project, Brexit Changes in labeling):
- Creating and managing company standard and guideline documents about design, color scheme, typography.
- Help create report deliverables using charts, tables, and other graphics Participate in calls/meetings with internal teams.
- Conducting knowledge sharing meeting about tool using and following company standards.

- Communicating and managing a team of ten graphic designers.
- Creating cost and time Estimates with graph and pie charts.
- Establish and promote design guidelines, best practices, and standards.
- Executing all visual design stages from concept to final hand-off.
- Support distinct phases of creative projects from concept to execution as needed.
- Ensure all projects and assets are on brand according to established brand style guides.

## IT Mech Solutions (Sr. Graphic Designer)

#### 19th Jan 2015 - April 2016, Vadodara

- Designing high-conversion landing pages.
- Design custom digital and print marketing material, as well as templates.
- Designing a variety of visual content, including social media graphics, decks, sales and marketing collateral, and white papers.
- Conceptualize and deliver design concepts for print materials (e.g., direct mail, Banner, Flyers, Visiting Cards, Logos, Brochure, Facebook Pages, Web Layouts and Templates, advertisements), internal and external communications, infographics, videos, presentations or for digital usage (e.g., websites, social media, email). Web Layouts and Templates: ecommerce, real estate, medical, restaurant, Personal profiles, Florist, Oil companies, Freight, Schools.
- Improving existing design elements to drive more leads to our partners.
- Create artwork for digital and print media.

## ClearPoint Learning Solutions (Visual Artist)

## 14th Jan 2013 - 7th Feb 2014, Pune

- Create graphics, animations, videos, and other visual elements using client brands/style guidelines.
- Creating Illustrations, Gaming Backgrounds.
- Create onscreen and downloadable infographics, job aids.
- Edit stock images and videos for eLearning courses.
- Create/edit background images used in eLearning courses developed in Storyline.
- Create/customize animated "characters/avatars."
- Create and enhance animation/videos using tools such as Adobe Flash.
- Design quizzes and meaningful course interactions in Articulate.
- Clients worked for: Johnson and Johnson, Novartis, Pfizer.

#### Indecomm Global Services (Web Programmer)

#### 10<sup>th</sup> Nov 2011 – 28<sup>th</sup> Dec 2012, Pune

- Xml conversion for an E-Learning course (by using xml and Flash) and creating new and modifying old graphics for the similar.
- Create graphics, animations, videos, and other visual elements using client brands/style guidelines.
- Create and enhance animation/videos using tools such as Adobe Flash.
- Design quizzes and meaningful course interactions in XML. \*Played lead role for the Cummins Project.
- Clients worked for: Morgan, Vecoo PAT, Cummins, Coles, and Con Edison.

# Languages Known

- English
- Hindi
- Kashmiri